Hello hello everyone how are you all I am
your personal advisor Amit Raj Sharma and
you are watching this real The credit for today's video goes to
Mr. Kunal Rana ji
he has commented in the comment section of the video of Ashok Income Plan of Aditya Birla Sun Life Insurance
Company Limited
If you all want to understand the details of The Assured Income Plan
with examples
then check the channel Life Insurance Playlist
you will get the video
with examples Mr. Kunal Rana ji
thank you very much for your comment because because of your
comment we will understand the secure plan
with examples Now as you all
know that every video
is according to your suggestions and questions so please encourage me by
liking the video and subscribing to the channel
and turning on the notification bell
If you have seen this video on Facebook
then like the page and like it and
tell in the comment section that you all
want to see the next video on your topic Let
us now understand the details of Secure Plan of Aditya Birla Sun Life
Insurance Company Limited
This plan is a no-land
participating plan A vestige in
simple words  If I understand, the
company will
automatically tell you in advance on the premium that you will pay, at the
time of taking the plan, how much return will you get. So,
this is a plan with guaranteed returns, in which
you get a life cover account,
which you will get normally in case of your death. We will
understand how it will be available with an example, but before that, let us
understand the eligibility criteria. The entries element is from
one year to 20 years. If you have taken this
plan for your child or you have taken it for
your child, then no
benefit will be valid until your child becomes an adult. You get premium and
benefit from 18 years to 70 years.
Now we will know the details of policy term,
premium payment term and income benefit
period. Watch the video
on full screen. If you take premium payment for six years, then
with it you can get a policy term of 6 years,
8 years,
10 years, 11 years, as you find
suitable. You will be able to take the policy term of Income
Benefit PM, which is 6 years, 9
years, 10 years and more. It will depend on
your entries.
You will get it accordingly. If the premium payment is for eight years,
then
you get the policy term option of 8 to 13 years and the
income benefit period remains the same, 6, 8,
10, 12, whichever you like. You will be
able to choose one. With the premium payment of 10 years,
you
get the power system option of 10 years to 15 years. The income
benefit remains for 12 years with charger.
You will be able to choose whichever you like. If you
take the premium payment of 12 years, then
with 12 years, you get the policy term option of 14 years, 15, 16, 17 years.
Their
benefit will remain the same as per the policy option. Okay,
now the question here will be what is the minimum
premium limit, the basic premium
per annum, and what is the
maximum premium of Rs 50,000. It depends on what
is the eligibility and what is the maximum limit of understanding according to the underwriting rules
and regulations
because the minimum
understanding is limited and  The maximum is Rs 3.5 lakh.
Your financial condition and
ability depend on your house. Drafting is done
accordingly. Now
we will understand the benefits and its illustration as well. The
main benefit of the state is the first one,
your death benefit. Second is income benefit.
Third is your loyalty addition. Loyalty
addition. You get income benefit on it. If
you have paid all the premiums on time, then let's take an
example. Suppose this is Mr.
whose age is Unnat this year and he is
taking a plan for short term, that is, a
policy term of six years, only
premium paying term of six years and along with that, he is
taking the income benefit period of only six
years. In such a situation, the annual premium he is paying
here is Rs 65 thousand
annually. Basically, I am paying here. This is
understood as an example. Keep that thing in mind.
Now, to understand this, we will
need a scooter and a tractor. Unnat is
13.1 years old, so our understanding here will be a
tractor, not its juice, that you are seeing that  The
slanted number written in front of the age of 30 years is
not 30, it will be yours, it has been misprinted,
I am telling you this so that if
you do not get confused on the telegram channel,
Pandit, if you read the PDF which I shared, then
on the news 13.1 what will we do,
our annualized premium is
65000, we will multiply it by *, then it will be
eight lakh 51 thousand ₹500,
here we will have a basic understanding, I want to
know what is the benefit in this plan, so let us force you
that 5 years are completed,
here there is death, sir,
in this plan the death benefit which
you would have got during the policy term,
your nominee, so it is wise,
on the total premium in 5 years, that here 3 lakh 25 thousand 000 has been withdrawn,
we have taken out one hundred and fifty percent
amount, it will be four lakh 27 thousand 500, if we
compare it with the basic understanding, then the basic understanding which is the
note of eight lakh 51 thousand 500 rupees, which will be more,
that will be the death benefit  Which will be given to the nominee
of Shrimant, okay, so this is
how the calculation will be done here, if
that were the case then the understanding person is that
we would remember it in this way, as I
told you, now see normally there will be an
option or if you take the policy, at that time
you can decide below, the
health benefit was
taken in installments of five years, in such a situation, if the
benefit is taken on annual mode, then
21.75 8 percent of the total benefit will be
received every year for 5 years, it will become
160.0 2% of the total benefit,
if it is taken monthly then it will be 1.8 49 2%, the total will
increase to 11010
16.95 2% of the total health benefit, now we
assume here that the
nominee of Shriman wants to take the death benefit in monthly installments, then he will
withdraw Rs. 8 lakh 51 thousand 500, 1.84
0.2%, so this would come  It is 15 thousand 743 decimal 93
paise, so see, if you want, you
can plan how to do the calculation, that is why
I have told you here, okay, now
we have to go to the income benefit here, that is the
income benefit, it is served hot, so
sir, we have assumed that we will survive and serve
chilli and till now the income
benefit here is 27.5 pass percentage
and the relative 50% of loyalty addition, from
where did we get this rate, we will
tell you, the rate of your income benefits depends on the radio
jockey tuition and Priya bed,
like if we
take a premium of 65000 here, then our bank is
coming in bank, if our premium was at least
₹75 10 and less than 1.5 lakh, then it
comes in bank, if our premium was
1.5 lakh rupees and less than 3 lakh, then the
bank would come for free and if the
annual premium was 3 lakh rupees, but if it was
less than 5 lakh, then it would come in bank for, so in this
way  The bank has been decided here on the
basis of which the income benefit rate and the
loyalty addition rate are decided there.
Okay, now on the basis of this band, the
income benefit rate varies on the basis of the benefit period taken.
Our income benefit period here is 16 years,
premium payment on 5th September is of 16 years and the
entry place is less than 50 years, then
our income benefit rate is 87.50 percent
which will be applied
on the annual basic premium. So now we have come to know here
that in reality the income benefit
rate depends on the entry,
premium payment on post, medium
benefit on back and also on the premium. Right now the
loyalty addition amount is
calculated on our income benefit.
In Bank One, our premium was being charged, so
50% became our loyalty addition rate. So
I also came to know that the
loyalty addition rate is also the entry, policy term
premium, how much is the PPT, how much is it  It
depends on that and one thing you should
understand very carefully is that even when the policy term is
completed, the income benefit
period starts and only then you start getting
income benefit as per the mode you must have heard.
What we will do to know the first installment is
income benefit comment audition search mountain. If we
add both then our annual
income benefit mode will come out
that the first installment will come out to be 65
thousand 710. If we take out 50% then it will be less than 56873
and if we take out up to 50% of 56 thousand 875 then 28
thousand 437. The camera quality addition of age 50 page will be there,
we will add both here.
Your first installment will come out to be
income benefit which will be
85,000 312 plus 50 paise. Now we have to
know the total amount of corporation benefit, so
what will we do in it, we will add * of six
because our income benefit
is behind.  511000 875 rupees, it
is guaranteed that you will get a total income benefit of Rs. 10,000. Now,
if you wish, you
can also avail the income benefit in half-yearly sickness monthly installments.
If you avail the premium, it is the annual income benefit,
49 percent of that installment, if you avail it quarterly, then it is
24.25 percent. And if you avail the
premium, then you can get eight percent of the annual income benefit. Okay, now along with this, if you want to avail a lump sum, you can also avail it. For example, if these complaints have been initiated and the life insurance of our Mr. has maturity, he can avail the
income benefit and he had died, in
such a situation, his normal income
benefit will be given to him in the same manner as
Mr. was getting it,
but if the nominee wishes, he
can also avail a lump sum amount. In such a situation, by
reducing this lump sum benefit amount, the life insurance amount will be given to someone.
If the life
shot remains alive, the policy term is completed and is about to become incomplete
and when
maturity comes, he feels that I should
take the loan amount, then he
can say this to the insurance company. Aslam, the respect that I can get will
depend on the insurance companies.
How to do the hotel calculation here, that
mainly it has been told in the form of income benefit only.
Now in the next part we will understand about the
calculation of surrender value, reduce
PWB calculation, loan. You
watched the video till the end and asked us a question,
thank you very much for that. You understood one thing and
explain to others also that insurance
is protection and protection is never
taken incomplete. You will get all the updates on the Telegram channel,
so thank you very much.